Finding Aid for George C. Steeh papers, 1971-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George C. Steeh papers 1971-1973
Steeh, George C.
0.3 linear feet
8698 Aa 2
Law student at University of Michigan; administrative assistant to Michigan Democratic State Senator John T. Bowman. Legislative log recounting debate over Congressional reapportionment in the Michigan Legislature; case study entitled, "Congressional Redistricting in Michigan After the 1970 Decennial Census"; and letter received by John Bowman on the subject of cross-district busing.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by George C. Steeh (donor no. 5445 ) in 1973.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
In the early 1970s, George C. Steeh, a law student at the University of Michigan, served as an administrative assistant to Democrat State Senator John T. Bowman. He was hired to gather data and study the problem of Congressional redistricting. Redistricting was then a highly controversial issue as the redrawing of districts was a powerful political tool. For the average citizen, redistricting also affected educational patterns and had implications for the issue of cross-district busing then being argued in the legislature and in the courts.
The George C. Steeh collection is comprised of those records created from his period of service to Senator Bowman. Included is a series of folders which Steeh labeled his "Legislative Log." Covering the period of January to May 1972, the log consists of Steeh's daily notes on Bowman's actions and maneuvers during the debate over Congressional redistricting in the State Legislature. This is followed by an extensive (174 p.) narrative and analysis of the Michigan redistricting struggle entitled, "Congressional Redistricting in Michigan after the 1970 Decennial Census: A Case Study." Steeh based his analysis upon the work he did for Bowman, a series of interviews with the principal participants in the redistricting debate, and examination of the Senate and House Journals and newspaper coverage of the debate. Beyond this, the collection includes a scattering of correspondence received by Bowman on the issue of cross-district busing.
Subjects:
Apportionment (Election law)--Michigan.; Bowman, John T., 1921-; Busing for school integration--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature.; Steeh, George C.; Students--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Redistricting
  - Legislative Log
    - January 1972 (Box 1)
    - February 1972 (Box 1)
    - March 1972 (Box 1)
    - April 1972 (Box 1)
    - May 1972 (Box 1)
  - Collected correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    (Letters to John T. Bowman from George Steeh, Marvin R. Stempien, as well as other correspondents)
  - "Congressional Redistricting in Michigan After the 1970 Decennial Census: A Case Study," November 6, 1973 (Box 1)
- Cross-District Busing
  - Collected correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    (Letters to John T Bowman from his constituents and his responses)